hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.comlisteningtime
to receive my listening practice
seminars bonus podcast episodes and my
sound training videos okay today i'm
going to talk about fads from the past
first of all we need to define the word
fad a fad is something that becomes
really popular really fast and then
eventually becomes forgotten for a while
it seems like everyone is excited about
this thing and follows the trend but
after a while they move on to the next
big thing often this is because people
are more interested in it just because
everyone else is
you don't necessarily love this thing
you just get caught up in the excitement
so let's go through some popular fads
from the past one of the fans i remember
as a kid was healy's shoes these are
shoes that have wheels on the heel of
the shoe the word heel just refers to
the back part of your foot so tons of
kids started wearing these shoes and
they would kind of skate around as they
walked skateboarding and other wheel
sports have always been considered to be
pretty cool so i think that's why
healeys became so popular i have to
admit that i thought they were pretty
cool but i didn't end up buying them
these shoes still exist today and
sometimes i see kids wearing them which
takes me back to my childhood a little
bit alright the next fad that i want to
talk about is furby furbies are these
little electronic toys that look like
owls if i remember correctly they talk
sing and do other stuff like that they
come in a lot of different varieties so
you can choose the one that you think is
the best or cutest this bad was huge
when i was a kid for some reason
everyone wanted a furby and i saw them
everywhere to be honest i was always
kind of freaked out by their eyes
they're really big and it just seems
like they're always following you but
maybe that's just me nowadays i have no
idea if these furry little toys are
still sold but one thing's for sure
furbies were all the rage at one point
alright one fad that i actually got
caught up in as a kid was beanie babies
beanie babies are these small animals
that are stuffed with beans instead of
the normal soft stuffing you can feel
the texture of the beans inside one of
their most recognizable features is the
red heart-shaped tag attached that says
tie for thai incorporated beanie babies
became a huge fad in the late 90s i can
remember collecting them as a kid and
always wanting more i can't say for sure
how many i ended up with but it was a
lot alright one last fad that i
completely forgot about is livestrong
bracelets and other wristbands
livestrong bracelets were these yellow
silicone gel bracelets that people
started buying and wearing in 2004 to
raise funds to support people affected
by cancer what started out as a noble
cause very quickly became a fashion
trend across america i remember when i
was in fifth grade i started seeing
these bands everywhere in all honesty i
wanted one of these bands just because
everyone else had one i never ended up
getting one but i did get some other
wristbands what's funny is that people
started wearing all kinds of different
wristbands not just these live strong
bands i had a handful of different
colored ones that i wore every day for a
period of time i remember matching the
color of my wristband with the color of
my clothes needless to say i bought into
this fad 100
okay that's all for today leave a
comment and tell me about a fad that you
remember from the past before you go
make sure to download the listening time
podcast and become a member at
patreon.comlisteningtime
to receive my listening practice
seminars bonus podcast episodes and
sound training videos also subscribe to
the channel click on the bell and follow
us on instagram i'll see you next time